<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Sastibe&#39;s Data Science Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Sastibe&#39;s Data Science Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Scalable RStudio Instance in AWS</title>
      <link>/2018/01/setting-up-a-scalable-rstudio-instance-in-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/setting-up-a-scalable-rstudio-instance-in-aws/</guid>
      <description>Assume you want to start to write R code (a very good decision, in my opinion) and you want to be able to write and test code whereever you are. Wouldn’t it be awesome if one could set up an environment that can be used for R coding independent of any device? Where all you need is a decent browser, a working internet connection and you’re good to go?
Obviously, that is the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking AWS Instances with MNIST classification in R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/benchmarking-aws-instances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/benchmarking-aws-instances/</guid>
      <description>In a previous postI have shown you how to setup an AWS instance running the newest RStudio, R, Python, Julia and so forth, where the configuration of the instance can be freely chosen. However, there is quite a lot of possibilities of instance configurations out there, just check out the drop-down menu on the page itself:
…why is it ‚nano‘, ‚micro‘ but then ‚large‘ ‚extra large‘? Be consistent, dangit!
 These instances differ in two dimensions: price and performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dbplyr vs dplyr: A benchmark test for SQL integration in R</title>
      <link>/2018/01/dbplyr-vs-dplyr-sql-integration-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/dbplyr-vs-dplyr-sql-integration-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Best Practices for Accessing Data from R? In a data science project, there are usually three parts of the process one has to cover: Data to Decision to Delivery. The first part, Data, has to answer the question “How do I make the data available for the Data Scientist?”. Quite often, the answer to this question involves some form of “Just access the Database XY from your wonderful, fantastic R Data Science machine[^1], and you’re done”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing a Web of Citations Using the Google Scholar API and D3.js</title>
      <link>/2018/01/visualizing-a-web-of-citations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/visualizing-a-web-of-citations/</guid>
      <description>“I am very glad you asked me that, Mrs. Rawlinson. The term ‘holistic’ refers to my conviction that what we are concerned here is the fundamental interconnectedness of things.” Douglas Adams, “Dirk Gently’s Holistic Agency”
 Networks are everywhere. The internet, road infrastructure and even the cast list of a theater show: depending on the interpretation, all kinds of entities can be viewed as networks.
One particularly interesting subset of networks is made up by scientific research papers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>